You know that 65% of health expenses are
borne by us from our own pocket.
Desire for good health and
wellness. Today, the inpatient hospitalization expenses in your health insurance policy are covered by
OPD expenses
like doctor consultation and diagnostic
tests. These are not covered
in most of the policies, especially if you are young
then the chances of hospitalization are very less. Most of the
expenses you incur are
OPD expenses, in which you have to
see a doctor for
cold and cough and you will have to visit the doctor.
They have prescribed some diagnostic tests which
your Health and Choice policy does not cover.
So, there is a solution for this and
today in the field of health care, we will talk about what
is health care, which plans have come
and how are they beneficial for you.
Please note this is not a recommendation video,
it is an information video. Do your
due diligence and take a look at the plan yourself before signing up.  I
would like to introduce myself to those who are new, my name is
Goodlink Kaur. For those who are new, I am a Certified
Financial Planner. I have been
associated with the insurance industry for the last 18 years and
every week I bring videos for you to help you in
your personal financial well-being and make your life easier and a
happy one because our company's
tagline is also creating wealth of
happiness. This video
is already available on our YouTube channel. So, on your
demand, I gave you details. So, this is a
detailed video.
So, it is a platform where different plans are
available according to different needs.
So, the benefit available in these plans
is unlimited doctor consultation from anywhere
in India. So,
you can consult any kind of doctor. You can
consult a doctor in any specialization. Otherwise,
if you want to consult these doctors, then the
cost is very high.
So, if the doctors of this company
prescribe any test, then that too
Diagnostic tests are given to you for free
today but only managed care program is available in your package and preventive
health initiative,
so your
prevention is also being focused on
because since childhood we have been hearing that
prevention is important, if you do prevention then there will be
no need for tax, there will be no need for
hospitalization,
and this is not an insurance company, it is not
regulated by IRDA but these insurance
plans are in partnership with IRDA approved
companies, so I am sir, now your question will be whether
this is health
insurance or not, and if it is not health and
valor, then how is it different from health and valor,
so this is not health insurance, it is a
health provider who
actively helps you to stay
healthy, their team of experienced doctors
understands your health profile
and gives you suggestions accordingly,
advises you on how to
manage your health so that the long
term results are good and you will have to
minimize hospitalization
in the future.  In short, if you want to understand, health
insurance is available to us when we go to
hospitals, where it comes to you
with regular doctor visits and
regular consultations, and if
hospitalization is required, that too is done
through group insurance. So now
you will ask about
which plans are available in the plans and
what are the benefits, so let's
talk about it in detail. So and care
plans offer you One Lite and
Plus, other One Essential So and Care is the
basic plan where
you get unlimited video consultations
with the doctor and with in-house specialists
like nutritional, physiotherapy,
psychologist etc., which are available in So and Lite, along with that
you can also consult external specialists and
get free tests, you get pan India access
and approved diagnostic centers, and Plus
is a slightly more upgraded version where you have the
features of So and Care and Lite, along with that
you get cashless hospitalization,
which is their  There are group insurance partners
through them and Essential is the latest offering
where you get all the features of Pay Care along with
cashless hospitalization plus
discount and test partner facilities.
So here you have seen that different plans
are available but we all have
different needs. Our retirement is
different. We all have different lifestyles and family
sizes are different, so our plan selection will also be
different. So these plans offer you
Care, Lite, Plus and
Essential. We are looking at three plans here.
Plus, Essential
and Cash. Let's talk about the difference in the plans
and what will be the coverage scope,
what is there or not in the cupboard. So, it's
your decision, so first we will
talk about unlimited video consultation and
in-house doctor. These are available in all these three plans.
In Essential, Care, there is unlimited
consultation with in-house nutritionist,
physiotherapist, psychologist. All these three
plans are available in Plus and Essential.
Personal Life Care is their Mancare Management
Program, which is available
in all three plans. So now let's talk about free health
checkup.
Free health checkup is available in Plus and Essential. Up to Rs 1
crore health and family coverage is available on the shoulder.
In Plus and Essential, this is made
available through their group
insurance partners, which are IIT
regulated health insurance companies,
and is made available from there.
You get helmet orange color
emergency care across India covered
in both the plans.
This is not available in Plus and Essential.
You also get tax savings under 80d tax saving in Class 12 and Class 12 and
Essential because it also has a health
insurance component. Prescription
blue and radiology tests are also covered. Whatever the
incident doctor prescribes to you,
it is covered in OPD only. This is free in Plus
and Essential.
Tests are available at discounted prices.
Last is consultation with non-
intentional doctors who are not on the panel of the IIT.  There is an
event doctor,
consultation with external specialists
is also included in which plan and in Plus,
this feature is not available in any other plan.
Now let's look at the pricing a little bit. So, the plan starts
at a low cost of Rs.
896,
starts at Rs. 565 per month and the plan
starts at Rs. 339 per month. Plus is a no-cost
option right now. So now we will see their LED
criteria and scope of coverage. So the
entry is from one to 65 years. The
duration of the plan is Rs. 1 year which is
standard with every car. This plan is
valid pan India.
So pan India you can also do it on the phone.
You get the option to pay upfront
or through EMI. Free health checkup is
given on boarding. When you are on
board, that is, with EMI, you are given a country health
checkup. Now let's talk about
what is excluded and what is
not covered. First, maternity expenses will
not be covered, second, dental.  Treatments are also
not covered, such as root canal treatment or
implants, then that is also
not covered. Thirdly, any expenses from IVR onwards are
also not covered. Fourthly,
medicines that are prescribed to you
in OPD are also not covered by the government, so
your pharmacy will not be covered. So, other
things that are covered in health insurance, such as
cosmetic surgeries, are not covered by
adventure sports, self-
conflicting injuries are not covered by kabaddi,
so you will not be covered here either. So
here I would like to tell you that
your coverage starts after you buy the plan,
from Devan, but there are some conditions which are not covered for 3 years. There are
some standard conditions
which are not covered for 1 year. I am
sharing the list of those with you. So, this is the list of
standard exclusions for 1 year.
You will see that these are the same conditions which are
taken for slow growing illnesses, which will
not be covered for one year. And
plans like cancer, prostate hernia,
chronic kidney disease.  Diabetes, Ischemic Heart
Disease, Very Common Venous, Internal Cancer Anomaly,
Anshova, this is the list of plans which will
not be covered. So now you will ask about the
plans. You have already told me
which plans are available,
what is the scope of the plan, what are the exclusions in the plans,
what is the eligibility
criteria. Now we will talk about how you
can buy these plans. So I will
share with you the steps by which
you can onboard these plans.
So first you will select the plan. You will
go to their website and visit www.india.in and
there different plans will be displayed to you.
You will select which plan you
want. After selecting the plan, you will be
asked to enter your mobile number. When you
enter your mobile number, enter your last
name, email ID and give an OTP. You will get an OTP to
verify it. Then
you will have to fill in the
name and date of birth of your family members. So, IT bill, last date,
health condition, surgery, if you have done any prior information, on that
basis you will be
given membership. So, help to you.
After checking the profile, you will be given membership. The
system will ask you to make the payment,
so you can use the promo code here,
GKT, zero, or three. Just
make the payment and fill the help question, on that
basis you will get the membership.
Now you have taken the plan, but we have become so used to i-commerce that
if someone is
not satisfied with the plan or we are not happy
with any feature or we feel that it is not
required, there is a
refined cancellation process as well, so the cancellation
process is quite simple. You have a
free cancellation available, which is available in insurance for
15 days, that is also available here,
if you do not understand, you can
cancel it in 15 days without any other charge,
and if you cancel after 15 days, then
you will be refunded with some deduction. I am
sharing the table of deductions with you, if after 15 days are over,
you cancel in another 7 days  If you cancel
then you will get 90% refund If you cancel in 60 days
then you will get 65% fund If you cancel
in 180 days then you will get 25% If the
days exceed 240 then you will
not get any refund Help in hand is a surprise
I would like to tell you again that while
taking health you give full disclosure in the health section so it is
important to give that disclosure here so it is important to give full health information
You will fill the help question
give all the information If the doctor of Awan feels then
he can also call you to investigate
and can also cross
verify you So once you have
D Awan membership then
you can do it through their application
But for your OPD and IPD needs then
you will download the application And
after downloading the application if you want to take
any doctor consultation
If you need hospitalization then
you can call on this number of Awan  So the
support team of Aavan will help and guide you
through the process and not only that, the
team of Aavan will support you in the entire claim
process, if you have to do any paperwork or anything else,
they will support you so that you can
focus on your help, the responsibility for the rest of the things is
theirs. So and in
conclusion, I would like to say that Aavan Health
Care is a platform where you
can take different plans as per your need, if you want to
brush OPD or get a
diagnostic test done or
you want an all-in-one plan which
also includes health insurance, then you
can go through it once,
you will also find their policy terms and conditions on the website,
all the
details are available there, so before signing up, do read
your due diligence, which
I always do, it is
very important to watch this video before
signing up for any financial product,
so if you find the video useful, then you
can share it with your friends and family and I had given you a code, do use it,
if you Aavan
Before knowing this, I would like to give a reminder that
if you have not subscribed to our channel, do
subscribe so that you get the
right information.